retentionscience.com 2016-05-16

# Privacy Policy | Retention Science

**Retention Science Privacy Statement**  
This privacy statement describes the policies and practices of Retention Science, in collecting, using, and safeguarding the private information that may be obtained through use of each company's products, services and websites including member's portal and public-facing website (collectively and individually referred to herein as "Retention Science"). Questions about this privacy policy may be submitted by an email to support@retentionscience.com. This privacy policy applies to each of the Retention Science entities, but not to Retention Science's partners or affiliates, which may have separate privacy policies.

**Information Collection**  
Personal information is collected from customers only after obtaining consent, which is obtained when customers are prompted for information when subscribing to the services, by using a Retention Science website, downloading a product, or requesting further information. Personally-identifiable information is not collected when a user simply browses the website. Retention Science may contact customers about offers and opportunities from Retention Science or its business partners, to conduct surveys, and gather feedback. This privacy statement does not extend to any information that is beyond the control of Retention Science.

**Services**  
Enrolling in Retention Science's subscription service may require a customer to provide certain personal information and enter into a Subscriber Agreement. Nothing herein is intended to modify the terms in the Subscriber Agreement.

**Product Download**  
Downloading a product will often require the input of personal information. This information will be used by Retention Science or its affiliates to contact the customer about Retention Science's products and services, including product updates and associated promotional material. This information may also be used as collated general demographic information to improve Retention Science's products and services.

**Cookies**  
A cookie is a piece of data stored on a computer's hard disk containing information about the owner. Retention Science may employ the use of cookies for measuring usage and access information. Our partners may use cookies. Retention Science does not exercise any access or control of such cookies.

Retention Science's websites use Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google, Inc. ("Google"), to evaluate the use of the Retention Science site. Google Analytics places a third party cookie on your computer that is then used to compile reports of visitor traffic and internet usage. Google analytics does not have a database of individual profiles for each visitor and only collects aggregate data.

**Log Files**  
Retention Science uses log files comprising of non-personally identifiable information to analyze trends, administer the site, track movements throughout the site, calculate the number of document and file downloads, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use.

**Sharing**  
Information provided to Retention Science will be protected by Retention Science and not sold or rented to any unrelated third parties without the express consent of the information provider, except that Retention Science may disclose data to its affiliates and business partners who have established similar privacy standards, when legally obligated to do so, or if disclosure is required to protect the rights over Retention Science, Retention Science's customers, or the users of Retention Science's services. Retention Science may also share aggregate demographic data that does not contain any personally identifiable information.

**External Links**  
The Retention Science website contains links to external websites which are outside the scope of this privacy statement. Retention Science is not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites and does not control the accuracy of information displayed by such websites.

**Forums, Bulletin Boards, Testimonials, Chat Rooms, and Surveys**  
Personal information submitted through a forum, bulletin board, testimonial, or chat room operated by Retention Science may be collected, used, and read by third parties, including other users. Retention Science is not responsible for any information submitted through these services. We occasionally request information from customers via surveys. Participation in these customer surveys is voluntary. Survey information is used to improve this web site and our services and products.

**Security**  
Retention Science protects information both online and off-line. The transmission of information is encrypted and protected using Secure Sockets Layer[(SSL)](http://www.instantssl.com/?key5sk0=1910&key5sk1=c93e34d5c480d487ae8d5d8010681f857c2e9fd6). Stored customer information is kept in a secure environment where access is restricted to employees who need the information to perform a specific job. Employee access is dictated according to the Retention Science Access Control Policy.

**Choice / Opt out**  
Customers may occasionally receive information on products and services,from Retention Science or may receive informational newsletters. Customers are given the opportunity to 'opt-out' of having information used for purposes not directly related to the Retention Science service at the point where the information is requested. Customers may also elect not to receive additional promotional communications using the opt-out link provided in each promotional. Customers may not opt-out of receiving service announcement updates as they contain important security information about the services.

**Amendments**  
Retention Science reserves the right to amend this privacy statement at any time. Any amendment will be made by posting the changes to the website. Customers must check the website periodically to be aware of any changes to the privacy statement. Your continued use of the website or Retention Science product or service constitutes your acceptance of those changes.
